Guide to the Ethelbert Nevin Collection, 1834-1980 CAM.NEV.1987.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Music, 1881-1903; I.
  - Manuscripts by Nevin, 2.
    - Other Manuscripts, E.
      - [originally in red leather folder], 1875 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 145)
        - Barcarole [sic]/Text: P. Dupont, 1881 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item b)
          Also included is a cover sheet in ink and a yellow lined paper with notes on the score.
        - Rose-bud/Text: Goethe (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item c)
          Rose-bud / Text: Goethe. 1 score ([5] p.); 35 cm. Holograph in ink, incomplete. For voice and piano [in G]. Marked Op. 3. Howard no.: B3
          Also included is a yellow lined paper with notes on the score
        - The Choristers. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item d)
          The Choristers. 1 score ([2] p.); 33 cm. Holograph sketch, in pencil. For mixed voices. Howard no.: B 5.
          Also has a yellow lined paper with notes on the score
        - The Choristers (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item e)
          The Choristers. 1 score ([2] p.): 34 cm. Holograph in ink, fair copy. For mixed voices. Howard no.: B 6.
        - Night Song/Text: Goethe, 1880 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item f)
          Night Song / Text: Goethe—Aug. 16, 1880. [2] p.; 34 cm. Holograph signed, incomplete pencil sketch For mixed chorus. Howard no.: B 7
        - Cradle Song/Text: Bowens, 1880 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item g)
          Cradle Song / Text: Bowens—Mar. 14, 1880. 1 score ([1] p.); 34 cm. Holograph signed, in pencil, with blue pencil corrections. Incomplete. Howard no. B 8.
        - A Song of a Boat/Text: Jean Ingelow, 1883 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item h)
          A Song of A Boat / Text: Jean Ingelow—Jan. 6, 1883. [1] p.; 33cm. Holograph, in pencil. For voice and piano. Melody line only. Howard no.: B9.
        - Tell Her, Oh! Tell Her/Text: Thomas Moore, 1882 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item i)
          Tell Her, Oh! Tell Her / Text: Thomas Moore—Mar. 3, 1882. [1] p.; 34 cm. Holograph in ink, with corrections. Incomplete. For voice and piano. More sketches on the back. Howard no.: B 10.
        - The World's Way (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item j)
          The World's Way [1] p.; 33 cm. Holograph sketch, in pencil, incomplete. For chorus. Howard no.: B 11.
        - [An Angel's Smile] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item k)
          [An Angel's Smile]. [2] p.; 27 cm. Holograph in ink. For voice and piano. Howard no.; B 12.
        - [Marriage Hymn], 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item l)
          [Marriage Hymn]. [2] p.; 33 cm. Holograph in pencil. For chorus. Inscribed: to Eliz. Jennings on her wedding day with warm affection from Ethelbert Nevin, May 29, 1900. Howard no.: B 13.
        - A Bird Song/Text: Rebecca B. Foresman (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item m)
          A Bird Song / Text: Rebecca B. Foresman. 1 score ([2] p.): 34 cm. Holograph in ink. Complete fair copy. For voice and piano. Melody same as piano piece "The Thrush." Howard no.: B 14.
        - [Not a Sparrow Falleth] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item n)
          [Not a Sparrow Falleth] [7] p.; 34 cm. Holograph, incomplete ink sketch. For mixed chorus, and piano. Anthem. Howard no.: B15
        - [The Sun, the Rose, the Lily] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item o)
          [The Sun, the Rose, the Lily] [1] p.; 35 cm. Holograph sketch, in ink, incomplete. For voice and piano. Vocal line only. Howard no.: B 16.
        - [Two Boats Rocked the River] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item p)
          [Two Boats Rocked on the River.] [6] p.; 35 cm. Holograph sketch, in pencil. Incomplete. For two voices, two instruments, and piano. Howard no.: B 17.
        - [A Mile and a Bittock] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item q)
          [1] p.; 35 cm. Holograph sketch, in pencil. For voice and piano. Howard no.: B 18.
        - Even at Winter Boometh a Springtide (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item r)
          [1] p.; 36 cm. Holograph, incomplete pencil sketch. For mixed voices. Howard no.: B 19.
        - Nocturne, 1883 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item s)
          [1] p.; 26 cm. Holograph in pencil. For piano. 4 measures. Howard no: B 21.
        - Scherzo, G Major (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item t)
          [2] p.; 26 cm. Holograph in ink, incomplete. For piano. Howard no: B 22.
        - Scherzo, A Major (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item u)
          [2] p.; 26 cm. Holograph in ink, incomplete. For piano. Howard no.: B 22a.
        - [Untitled] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item v)
          [12] p; in various pagings; 35 cm. Holograph in ink, incomplete. For voice and piano. Vocal line only. Howard no: B 23.
        - Romance (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item w)
          [1] p. of music; 26 cm. Holograph in ink. For violin. First 9 measures of violin part. Howard no.: B 24.
      - Cello/by F. Liszt (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 146)
        [Loose manuscripts in white folder] [1] p.; 34 cm. Ms. in ink. Cello part only, in E.
      - Etude (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 147)
        1 score ([2] p.); 25 cm. Holograph in ink, incomplete ink. For piano [in A flat].
      - Gavotte in E. major, 1881 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 148)
        [1] p.; 34 cm. Sketch in ink, incomplete. In unknown hand. In caption: Boston, Oct. 26, 1881. On back: another sketch in ink.
      - Gondolieri (Finale)/by Ethelbert Nevin; arr. for Violin and Piano by Arthur W. Devor (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 149)
        1 score ([1] p.); 31 cm. Holograph signed, in ink, fair copy.
      - The Highland Lad's Appeal, 1909 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 150)
        1 score ([2] leaves); 35 cm. Ms., fair copy. In caption: Adapted to melody by Ethelbert Nevin, and transposed by E.B. Chase. For voice and piano.
      - [If I Were a King] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 151)
        1 score ([2] p.); 34 cm. Holograph in ink, incomplete, with engraver's marks and corrections in pencil. For voice and piano.
      - Serenata, 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 152)
        [1] p.; 33 cm. Cover only. For piano, violin, and violincello. On cover: Op. 23, Firenze Jan. 1896, holograph in ink.
      - Valse, 1883 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 153)
        [2] p.; 24 cm. Holograph in ink, incomplete sketch. For piano [in F].
      - [As Mary Came with Rev'rent Feet, Gavotte] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 154)
        - As Mary Came with Rev'rent Feet, a. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item a)
          Holograph. Incomplete. For chorus and orchestra. Howard no: C 3
        - Gavotte, G major, b. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item b)
          Holograph sketch, in pencil and ink. 8 measures only. For string orchestra. Howard no: C 4.
      - Oft as I Rest in the Shade of my Bower (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 155)
        Holograph. Incomplete, with indications for orch. accomp. For soli, chorus, & orchestra. Howard no.: C 1 & C 2
      - [Waltz] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 156)
        Holograph, incomplete. For orchestra, in B flat. Howard no: C 8.
      - [Untitled] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 157)
        Holograph, incomplete. For orchestra, in B flat, meter: 2/2. Howard no: C 9.
      - [Manuscripts in green portfolio], 1887 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 158)
      - [Untitled] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 159)
        Inside of the Folder marked March 10, 1887 Wooster Manuscripts of unidentified sketches.
        - [Untitled] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item a)
          Holograph, incomplete. For orchestra, in D. Howard no: C 10.
        - One Spring Morning (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item b)
          Howard C11
        - [Untitled] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Item c)
          Holograph, incomplete. For orchestra, in G, meter: 2/2. Howard no: C 12.
  - Compositions by Others, 3.
    - Clutsam, G. H. Songs from the Turkish Hills, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 160)
      1 - The Snow on the Mountains. 2 - When I Hear Thee Sing. 3 - A Dream. 4 - I Know of Two Bright Eyes (Myrra). 5 - Tales They Tell. 6 - Let the Slaves.
    - Clutsam, G. H. Songs from the Turkish Hills, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 161)
      Cover only.
    - Sibella, Gabrielle. Villanella, 1917 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 162)
      A song with piano accomp. for a high voice.
      Schirmer publishing.
    - If the Deep Voice of Sorrow "Il Segreto"/Air from Donzetti's opera Lucrezia Borgia; sung by Gignora Pica; Eng. adaptation by George Loder, 1879 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 163)
      New York: William Hall & Son, [N.D.] 1 score ([5] p.); 36 cm. Inscribed: Bert W. Nevin, Jan. 1879, Sewickley Minstrels.
    - Galloway, Tod B. Seven Memory Songs (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 164)
      Op. 30. For Voice and Piano. Theodore Presser, Philadelphia, PA. 1) When Spring Comes Laughing. 2) The Gypsy Trail. 3) Love Comes Back. 4) Early One Morning. 5) Pickaninny Lullaby. 6) I Arise from Dreams. 7) Alone on the Housetops.
    - Gounod, Charles. The Redemption: A Sacred Trilogy, 1883 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 165)
      Written and Composed by Charles Gounod; pianoforte arr. by Berthold Tours. Eng. trans. by Rev. J. Trontbock, M.A. New York: G Schirmer, [N.D.]. 1 score ([xii, 149] p.); 27 cm. On cover: E.W. Nevin, Boston, Jan 12, 1883.
    - Housman, Rosalee. Three Songs (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 166)
      I. Tara Bindu. II. The Look (missing). III. The Rim of the Moon (missing). G. Schirmer, New York. "Alice Nevin" pencilled in at the top.
    - Lehmann, Liza. Nonsense Songs (the Songs That Came Out Wrong), 1908 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 167)
      Published by Chapell & Co, Ltd. Contents: I - Quartet - How Doth the Little Crocodile. II - Solo (Bass) - Fury Said to a Mouse. III - Duet (Tenor and Bass) - You are Old, Father William. IV - Solo (Contralto) - Speak Roughly to Your Little Boy. V - Quartet - Will You Walk a Little Faster? VI - Recit. (Contralto) - Oh! Tis Love. VII - Solo (Tenor) - Mock Turtle Soup. VIII - Solo (Soprano) - The Queen of Hearts. IX - Quartet - They Told Me You Had Been to Her. X - Epilogue - To Alice.
    - Liszt, Franz. The Preludes, 1889 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 168)
      Leipzig, Breitkopf & Märtel
    - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, Piano Sonata for four-hands, no. 1 in D Major, 1875 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 169)
      Dresden: Hoffarth's, [N.D.] on cover: B. W. Nevin, Dresden, Dec. 23, 1875.
    - Nevin, Arthur. *Were I a Star/Text? (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 170)
      Sketch. 1 score ([2] p.); 34 cm. Holograph. For voice and piano [in E flat]. Presented to the University of Pittsburgh with a note to Chancellor Bowman from Elizabeth Dickson.
    - Sears, Helen. Three Songs (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 171)
      Dedicated to Helen Abbott. 1. December (Op. 2, no. 1). 2. Phantoms (Op. 2, no. 2). 3. Bird of the Night (Op. 2, no. 3).
    - Boehme, Armin von. Zwei Lieder fur Mezzo-Soprano (oder Baryton) [Two Songs for Mezzo-Soprano or Baritone], April 1885 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 172)
      Berlin: Hermann Erler, [18--] 1 score ([4] p.); 35 cm. Contents: Op. 10. O Rede Nicht von Scheiden Op. 11 Aus Nantes aus Nantes. On cover: With the composer's compliments to his pupil Mr. Nevin at Pittsburgh, USA. From Dresden.
    - Christmas Carols (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 173)
      The Boston Music Company. Octavo Church Music. Cover Only
    - he Rosary: Music by Georgia B. Welles, 1903 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 3, Folder 174)
      Words by Robert Cameron Rogers. Published by Eclipse Publishing, Philadelphia, PA. For voice and piano (6 p.)
- Books, 1834-1936; II.
  This series contains books owned by Nevin and his family members, plus a biography written by Vance Thompson and a promotional pamphlet published by John Church Company. Arrangement is done alphabetically by author's names. Items located in Oversize Items or Photos and Objects.
  - Common Prayer (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 175)
    Given to E.W.N. at Edgwater by Mother Paul, before taking train to go to his wedding.
  - Common Prayer, 1884 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 176)
    Gift from E.W.N. before he sailed for Germany in 1884.
  - Nevin, Frank Taylor. A Table of the Descendants of Margaret Williamson, 1898 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 177)
    [14] sheets; 39 x 32 cm. Completed Sept. 3, 1898. Family Chart of E.W.N.
  - Sawyer, Frank E. Notes and Half Notes, 1896 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 178)
    New York: Putnam's Sons. vii, 109 p.; 18 cm. A letter from author's mother (Mary Sawyer) to E.W.N. laid in, dated Dec. 11, 1896.
  - Scheffel, J. V. Der Trompeter von Sakkingen: ein Sang vom Oberrhein., 1886 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 179)
    Stuttgart: Adolf Bonz. 280 p.; 17 cm. On t.p.: Anne from Bert, Berlin, Feb. 17, 1886. Text in German.
  - St. Pierre, Bernardin de. Paul and Virginia (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 180)
    London: George Routeledge and Sons, Ltd. 253 p.; 14 cm. Given to Walter Nevin by Mr. and Mrs. Ethelbert Nevin and was handed to Dr. George H. Clapp on Nov. 21 [1938] by Arthur Nevin to be added to his brother's collection. Walter Nevin was E.W.N.'s older brother.
  - MISSING Thompson, Vance. The Life of Ethelbert Nevin: From His Letters and His Wife's Memories, 1933 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 181)
    vii, 247 p.; 25 cm. A letter from Vance Thompson to Mrs. Nevin, pasted on fly leaves. Accompanying note: Donated to the University of Pittsburgh by Frederic Schaeffer in Feb. 1934.
  - Un Giorno in Venezia (A Day in Venice): Suite for the Pianoforte, 1898 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 182)
    Cincinnati: John Church. 1 booklet ([12] p.); 18 cm. Presented to the University of Pittsburgh by Mrs. Nevin, May 10, 1939. Also contains a receipt for this item and a program of the Rosary.
- Programs, 1851-1938; III.
  This category is divided into three subseries: Concerts by Nevin, Concerts of Nevin's music by others, and Other concerts. The items within each group are organized by the chronological order of the concerts. Other Programs list the programs of the concerts attended by Ethelbert Nevin and other family members.
  - Concerts by Nevin, 1851-1938; 1.
    - Farewell Concert by Sewickley Choral Club, Choral Hall, 1880 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 183)
      Bert. W. Nevin performed Lied des Meermadchen: "O Wie Wogt Es" by Weber (Mermaid's song from Oberon).
    - E.W.N. Piano Recital, December 10, 1886 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 184)
      Hamilton Music and Art Chamber. Fri. Eve. Assisted by Miss Belle Tomer, Soprano. Includes three of Nevin's songs: Starts of the Summer Night; Summer Longings; Oh! That we two were Maying.
    - Piano-Forte Recital by Ethelbert Nevin. Mr. Walter Bausman's Music Rooms, [Lancaster, PA], January 11, 1887 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 185)
      Mr. Walter Bausman's Music Rooms, [Lancaster, PA]. Assisted by Miss Hallie Bechtold.
    - Pianoforte-Concerto Concerts, March 8, 1887 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 186)
      Chickering Hall, [Boston]. Tues. afternoon. Second of F. J. Lang's series of "Pianoforte-Concerto Concerts." E.W.N. performed Liszt Concerto No.1 in E flat Major.
    - Pianoforte Recital by Ethelbert Nevin, March 11, 1887 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 187)
      Chickering Hall, [Boston]. Fri. Eve. Assisted by Miss Jennie Vorn Holz. Year written on program in pencil.
    - Ethelbert Nevin's Piano Recital, December 5, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 188)
      Carnegie Chamber Music Hall, [New York]. Miss Julia Wyman, vocalist. Only fragment.
    - E. W. N, Mrs. Julie Wyman, Miss Isadore Duncan, M'lle Severin, March 24, 1898 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 189)
      Carnegie Lyceum, [New York]. Thurs.
    - Nevin Piano Recital. Woman's Club of Sewickley Valley, February 21, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 190)
      Woman's Club of Sewickley Valley. Presented to the University by Willa Cather.
  - Concerts of Nevin's music performed by others, 1893-1938; 2.
    - Duquesne Conservatory of Music. Recital of Selections from the vocal and instrumental compositions of Ethelbert Nevin, to be rendered by Members of the Faculty and Advanced students, March 22, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 191)
      Recital of Selections from the vocal and instrumental compositions of Ethelbert Nevin, to be rendered by Members of the Faculty and Advanced students. Duquesne Conservatory of Music. Tues. Eve. Not listed in Wang list or word document.
    - MISSING Nevin Recital, given by Pupils of Charles F. Boylan, May 22, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 192)
      The residence of Mr. James Palmer, Jr., 243 Univ. Ave., Rochester, New York. Mon. Eve.
    - Memorial Concert: A Tribute to the memory of the late Ethelbert Nevin, March 8, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 193)
      St. Luke's Church, Dubuque, LA [?]. Fri. Evening.
    - Ethelbert Nevin's songs and piano compositions: Rendered by the pupils of Mrs. Charles F. Boylan, June 13, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 194)
      Thurs. Eve. Assisted by Mr. Maurice Moll, violinist.
    - Oak Manor Concert. Oak Manor, home of H. K. Porter, January 7, 1902 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 195)
      Oak Manor, home of H.K. Porter. Presented to the University by Willa Cather.
    - Nevin Week, September 1908 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 196)
      Egyptian Hall - The Wanamaker Store, [Philadelphia?]. Sept. 21-26 (inclusive). With a biographical sketch at the end.
    - "Le Rosaire", April 27, 1926 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 197)
      Theatre National de L'Odeon. A play based on the novel "The Rosary," written by Florence L. Barclay and on the music from "The Rosary" by Ethelbert Nevin. Received from Mrs. Nevin, May 18, 1939.
    - Charles Watt's piano recital made up exclusively of works of Ethelbert Nevin, 1938 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 198)
      A program of Ethelbert Nevin Music. The Sewickley Music Club Choral. Presbyterian Church Houses, Sewickley. Tues. March 29.
    - An Evening of Song: The Old Allegheny Festival Choir, February 26, 1983 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 199)
      Pual D. Weber, Music Director. Florence Gowers, Accompanist with Charlotte Day, Pianist, and Charles Cohen, Baritone. February 26, 1983, ~ the Presbyterian Church of Sewickley and February 27, 1983 ~ Synod Hall, Oakland, 8:00 p.m.
    - A program of Ethelbert Nevin Music, March 29, 1938 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 200)
      Presented by the Sewickley Music Club Choral. Not in Wang list or Word doc. finding aid. two copies
    - Centennial Program, 1938 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 201)
      Sewickley Presbyterian Church, 1838-1938. Sunday, April 24, 1938. Includes several of Nevin's pieces in the service.
  - Other Programs, 1851-1923; 3.
    - Mademoiselle Jenny Lind's Concert, 1851 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 202)
      [1851? New York?] Under the direction of M. Benedict. Laid in: a clipping on the biographical data on Jenny Lind; two other clippings; a letter to R.C.M. from A.P.N., stating the significance of this program, given to her by Father Nevin.
    - Philharmonische Concerte, Berlin, VI Season 1892-1893, October 17, 1892 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 203)
      Montag, Berlin. Under the direction of Dr. Hans von Bülow, R Maszkowske, Dr. Hans Richter. Herausgegeben und verlagt von der Concertdirection Hermann Wolff, Berlin; Redigert von Dr. H. Reimann. 1 v. ([24] p.); 21 cm. Accompanied by note from A.P.N. to R.C.M.: The last concert E.W.N. attended. One of the greatest ever given by these great artists.
    - Joseph and His Bretheren, a Play in Four Acts by Louis N. Parker, 1913 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 204)
      His Magesty's Theatre, [London]. Entrance ticket, dated Dec. 13, 1913, issued at Ritz Hotel, laid in.
    - The Story of the Rosary, by Walter Howard, a romantic play in four acts, December 20, 1913 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 205)
      Prince Theatre, Shaftesbury Ave., [W.C. London] Dec. 20, 1913 and every evening. Two copies.
    - Walter Howard's Play, "The Story of the Rosary," Told in Eight Pictures, 1913 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 206)
      Princes Theatre, Shaftesburty Ave., [W.C. London]. [Dec. 20, 1913]. Photo booklet keepsake.
    - "Mighty Lak'a Rose," Presented by Edwin Carewe, March 28, 1923 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 207)
      Mark Strand, Broadway at 47th St., New York. Sun. Advertisement and a clipping: "Nevin's Work Theme for Picture Production" (Feb. 11, 1923) laid in. Advertisement and clipping from program both filed separately.
    - "Mighty Lak'a Rose," Presented by Edwin Carewe, March 18, 1923; g. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 2, Folder 208)
      Program for Curtis Benton's play "Mighty Lak' a Rose" directed by Edwin Carewe at the Mark Strand Theater, March 18, 1923.
    - The Cantata of Don Munio, h. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 209)
      One page, lists Herbert Nevin as singing the part of Escobedo and John I. Nevin as singing the parts of Abadil and Roderigo.
- Clippings, 1888-1947; IV.
  This category is divided into four subseries: About concerts, Social events, Obituaries, and Other events.
  - Concerts, 1886-1902; 1.
    Arrangement is by chronological order.
    - Debut, December 11, 1886 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 210)
      "The Nevin Recital: The Welcome and Farewell of a Home Pianist," Pittsburg Commercial Gazette, Sat., Dec. 11, 1886. "A Master's Performance," The Pittsburgh Times, Sat.
    - Lancaster, January 11, 1887 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 211)
      "A Piano-forte Recital: An Evening of Rare Pleasure at Mr. Walter Abusman's Music Rooms." Lancaster, PA, [Jan. 12, 1887]. Another copy pasted at the back of the program at Chickering Hall, March 8, 1887. "An Evening of Harmony." Lancaster, PA, [Jan. 12, 1887]. Another copy pasted at the back of the program at Chickering Hall, March 8, 1887.
    - Chickering Hall, Boston, March 8, 1887 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 212)
      "Untitled," about his Liszt concerto.
    - Chickering Hall, Boston, March 11, 1887 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 213)
      "Mr. Nevin's Recital." Clipping pasted on paper backing.
    - Duquesne, March 28, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 214)
      "Untitled," pre-event announcement. "An Evening of Music," Pittsburgh. Mar. 29, 1893
    - Detroit, "Untitled", January 26, 1895 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 215)
      Detroit Free Press
    - Madison Square Concert Hall, 1898 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 216)
      "A Nevin Concert," The [New York] Criterion, Feb. 26, 1898. Assisted by Mr. Francis Rogers, Miss Genevieve Weaver, Mr. Paul Morgan (violin), Miss Geraldine Morgan (cello).
    - Steinert Hall, 1898 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 217)
      "Untitled" Concert assisted by Mr. Francis Rogers, Miss Genevive Weaver, Mr. Paul Morgan (violin), Miss Geraldine Morgan (cello).
    - Hotel Schenley, Pittsburgh, 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 218)
      "Untitled." "Untitled," The Pittsburgh Post, Mar. 28, 1900
    - Happenings in Society's Realm, March 28, 1900; j. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 219)
      Pittsburg Post Hotel Schenley recital.
    - Madison Square Concert Hall [---] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 220)
      [Pollard, Bercival] "Crochets and Quavers," Town topics.
    - Oak Manor concert at H. K. Porter Home, a tribute to E. W. N., January 7, 1902 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 221)
      "Untitled," The Pittsburgh Gazette, Wed., Jan. 8, 1902. "Untitled,"The Pittsburgh Dispatch, Wed., Jan. 8, 1902
    - "Much Interest" (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 222)
      Regards a performance of Nevin's music at the Duquesne Conservatory.
    - Program Announcement, December 6, 1933 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 223)